<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-07-04T09:17:15+00:00</updated><id>https://github.com/laurajul//canon/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Canon of Latent Spaces</title><subtitle>The project page of Canon of Latent Spaces : How large AI Models Encode Art and Culture. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Una Europa Summer School 2024</title><link href="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/blog/2024/una-europa-summer-school/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Una Europa Summer School 2024"/><published>2024-06-19T07:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-19T07:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://github.com/laurajul//canon/blog/2024/una-europa-summer-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/blog/2024/una-europa-summer-school/"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to announce that Maria-Teresa and Laura will be attending the Una Europa Summer School on AI and Creativity, hosted by the CEUB - Bertinoro Residential Center of the University of Bologna. This blended intensive program will take place from July 7-13, 2024.</p> <p><strong>Event Overview:</strong> The Una Europa Summer School brings together graduate and PhD students, as well as academics and creative professionals, interested in the intersection of artificial intelligence and various creative domains. Participants will explore topics such as AI in Literature and Visual Art, AI-Driven Music Composition, Computational Creativity, and more.</p> <p><strong>Program Details:</strong> For more information about the program, schedule, and topics covered, please visit the <a href="https://site.unibo.it/una-europa/en/summer-and-winter-school/summer-school-ai">Una Europa Summer School on AI and Creativity</a> official website.</p> <p><strong>Event Dates:</strong> July 7-13, 2024<br/> <strong>Location:</strong> CEUB - Bertinoro Residential Center, University of Bologna</p> <p>We look forward to engaging with cutting-edge research and discussions on AI and its applications in creative fields.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcement"/><category term="summerschool,"/><category term="AI,"/><category term="creativity"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Participation in Una Europa Summer School on AI and Creativity]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/assets/img/posts/summer_school_bologna.jpeg"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/assets/img/posts/summer_school_bologna.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry><entry><title type="html">Hidden Layers 2024</title><link href="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/blog/2024/hidden-layers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hidden Layers 2024"/><published>2024-06-12T15:12:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-12T15:12:00+00:00</updated><id>https://github.com/laurajul//canon/blog/2024/hidden-layers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/blog/2024/hidden-layers/"><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce that Maria-Teresa and Laura Wagner participated in the Hidden Layers conference, held from June 12-15 in Cologne, Germany. This event, hosted by Köln International School of Design (KISD) brought together a diverse group of experts to discuss and explore the relationship between artificial intelligence and design.</p> <p><strong>Event Overview:</strong> The Hidden Layers conference, organized by the KITeGG research project on design and AI, included a public program of talks, exhibitions, and workshops, as well as internal meetings of the five art and design schools involved. The conference aimed to explore the complexities of machine learning (ML) and artificial intelligence (AI) from a design perspective, addressing themes such as aesthetics, potentials, biases, and dangers within deep neural networks and large datasets.</p> <p><strong>Talk: Surface Aesthetics and Prompting in AI-Generated Art by Maria-Teresa de Rosa Palmini</strong> Maria-Teresa de Rosa Palmini presented a talk on “Surface Aesthetics and Prompting in AI-Generated Art.” Her presentation highlighted methods for creating visual content using text-to-image generative models and discussed the development of a specialized prompt language to achieve high-quality visual results. Through Natural Language Processing (NLP) and visualization techniques, she analyzed prompts that led to popular images on text-to-image platforms. Her analysis revealed a focus on surface aesthetics in prompts, emphasizing conventional beauty, popular visual themes, and the presence of erotic content. The findings provided insights into the language patterns that contribute to highly rated AI-generated art.</p> <p><strong>Workshop: Stable Diffusion dis-confusion by Laura Wagner</strong> Laura Wagner conducted a workshop titled “Stable Diffusion dis-confusion.” This hands-on session offered participants an in-depth look at the components of popular open-source text-to-image systems like Stable Diffusion by Stability AI. Participants explored the pipeline components that tokenize, condition, encode, decode, diffuse, schedule, sample, and upscale. The workshop emphasized the modularity of these pipelines and their potential for collaboration, providing practical experience in manipulating and recombining these modules to create new image-generation processes.</p> <p><strong>Conference Details:</strong></p> <ul> <li><strong>Date:</strong> June 12-15, 2024</li> <li><strong>Location:</strong> Köln International School of Design (TH Köln), Ubierring 40, 50678 Cologne</li> <li><strong>Themes:</strong> AI, Code &amp; Material; AI, Society &amp; (Visual) Culture</li> <li><strong>Organizers:</strong> Prof. Dr. Lasse Scherffig, Matthias Grund, Jakob Kilian, Dzennifer Zachlod</li> <li>Website: https://hiddenlayers.de/</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcement"/><category term="conference,"/><category term="talk,"/><category term="workshop"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Participation in Hidden Layers Conference 2024]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/assets/img/posts/hl-banner.gif"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/assets/img/posts/hl-banner.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry><entry><title type="html">Acceptance for the DSI Excellence Program</title><link href="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/blog/2024/dsi-excellence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Acceptance for the DSI Excellence Program"/><published>2024-05-27T07:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-27T07:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://github.com/laurajul//canon/blog/2024/dsi-excellence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/blog/2024/dsi-excellence/"><![CDATA[<p>Maria-Teresa and Laura will be joining the prestigious <a href="https://www.dsi.uzh.ch/en/education/excellence-program.html">DSI Excellence Program</a> starting this fall.</p> <h2 id="the-digital-society-initiative-dsi-excellence-program-at-uzh">The Digital Society Initiative (DSI) Excellence Program at UZH</h2> <p>The <strong>Excellence Program for PhD students</strong> at the University of Zurich is offered through the <a href="https://www.dsi.uzh.ch/en.html">Digital Society Initiative (DSI)</a>. This program is designed for new and prospective doctoral students interested in digital transformation. It serves as a complementary curriculum to a doctoral program, general doctorate, or doctoral subject.</p> <h3 id="what-is-the-goal-of-the-excellence-program">What is the goal of the Excellence Program?</h3> <p>The program aims to prepare doctoral students from all disciplines for an environment where interdisciplinary collaboration on digitalization topics is prioritized. It focuses on instilling new knowledge, skills, and abilities essential for thriving in a world that values interdisciplinary collaboration, critical evaluation, and interpretation of large digital datasets, and innovative solutions to significant epistemological questions.</p> <h3 id="program-benefits">Program Benefits</h3> <p>Participants in the Excellence Program will:</p> <ul> <li>Engage with research methods from various disciplines.</li> <li>Learn to critically reflect on the impacts of digitalization.</li> <li>Join an exclusive peer network.</li> <li>Receive funding for their own research and interdisciplinary projects.</li> </ul> <h3 id="scholarships-in-the-excellence-program">Scholarships in the Excellence Program</h3> <p>The DSI offers scholarships to outstanding doctoral students. Applications for these scholarships are accepted annually in line with SNF guidelines.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="announcement"/><category term="DSI,"/><category term="Education,"/><category term="Digital"/><category term="Transformation,"/><category term="Scholarship"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Acceptance for the DSI Excellence Program at UZH for interdisciplinary doctoral studies in digital transformation.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/assets/img/posts/2024-05-27-dsi-excellence.png"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://github.com/laurajul//canon/assets/img/posts/2024-05-27-dsi-excellence.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry></feed>